# Joe Simms

Senior Software Engineer

I am a software developer with 12+ years of experience. I co-founded Elevate Atlantic while participating in the Propel ICT start-up accelerator. Additionally, I have worked remotely with several teams to maintain and add features to existing applications. I am seeking a position as a Full-Stack Ruby on Rails Developer with a focus on Devops.

P: 306.290.3050 E: joe@joesim.ms A: Moncton, NB

## Experience

#### Senior Software Engineer @ REIN.ai (Chapel Hill, NC | Remote) Oct. 2019 - Present

REIN.ai is an insurtech start-up; its public-facing product is droneinsurance.com.

While at REIN, my responsibilities included full-stack development utilizing a micro-service architecture (Multiple Rails APIs, React Frontend, Redis for inter-service communication). I worked with a small team to build a new admin dashboard to support our existing products. The admin interface development included the consumption of existing APIs and the construction of new ones. This project required that I build a JWT consumer to integrate with our existing authentication mechanisms. In addition to development, I was responsible for deploying the new admin dashboard to our AWS based rancher infrastructure. I was required to dockerize the application as well as build and maintain its CircleCI configurations. I also migrated two of our other applications from outdated docker base images to alpine based ruby images built and maintained by the ruby community. I participated in regular code reviews. I mentored junior developers, and was available to pair with them when they encountered difficulties.

#### Contract Developer @ Once A Month Meals (Dayton, OH | Remote) April – Sept. 2019

Once A Month Meals is a Mommy-blog turned membership site to help members with meal planning.

I was brought on at Once a Month Meals to add a new nutrition label feature to their existing application. The architecture consisted of a Rails Backend API and Admin dashboard, coupled with a Wordpress frontend. For the nutrition label feature to work, we mapped every individual ingredient in our system to a matching ingredient in our nutrition data provider's database. The application would then calculate the nutrition information for each recipe based on the ingredients and amounts used. Each time a user requested a recipe, the nutrition facts were calculated. I built a Redis-based Russian-doll style caching system to store the nutrition information for each ingredient, caching at the ingredient level allowed for more cache hits when other recipes used the same ingredient. Due to licensing restrictions, we could only cache the data for 24 hours. To further increase the performance of the application, I built a rake task to identify the 200 most visited recipes from the previous day and warm the cache with the nutrition data for those ingredients.

#### Platform Engineer @ CloudApp (San Francisco, CA | Remote) May 2018 – Jan. 2019

CloudApp is a screenshot and video sharing service with applications for Mac, PC, and Mobile.

While at CloudApp, I was on the platform engineering team, and worked with a team to maintain and add new features to an aging microservice based application. The technologies used as CloudApp were varied; the main API was Rails back-end; however, the stack included AWS Lamda, GraphQL, and utilized S3 for file storage. The Frontend was a React-based application written in TypeScript. Though most of my work at

CloudApp was maintenance and minor feature work, I was also tasked with digging into AWS issues that we were having. I, along with one other developer, built a CloudApp Adobe XD Plugin. CloudApp was a partner with Adobe, and this allowed us pre-release access to the new plugin feature, and when Adobe publicly launched the XD plugins the CloudApp plugin was one of the ones featured.

#### Rails Engineer @ Eezy (Bowling Green, KY | Remote) July 2016 - May 2018

Eezy is a creative content distribution platform, operating more than ten sites.

The four main sites at Eezy were Rails-based and shared the same code base, hooks in the deploy script would customize the theming for each. While at Eezy, I worked on maintenance and new feature development on the aging monolith. Day-to-day tasks included working with and adding new features to our Solr implementation, creating perfect pixel HTML from PSDs, Dockerizing the application and API work. One of the more interesting assignments was the development of a Slack application for Vecteezy, which also required deployment to our AWS based infrastructure. Eezy also operated several Wordpress based sites that would occasionally require migration or other maintenance.

#### CTO / Co-Founder @ Elevate Atlantic (Halifax, NS | Remote) Oct 2014 - May 2018

Elevate Atlantic was a Services on-demand startup, initially we focused on snow removal and then later pivoted to other household services.

I, along with my business partner, founded the Elevate Atlantic. I was the technical co-founder and built the entire application, which consisted of a Rails-based application and an accompanying iOS and Android application for our contract partners. It utilized Stripe's Connect platform to charge customers and pay our contractor partners. The application was deployed on bare metal in an OVH Datacenter with Capistrano. Our early work with the company earned us access to the Propel ICT startup accelerator, where I learn ednumerous business best practices, which I have applied in all subsequent roles.

#### Senior Developer @ Current Studios (Halifax, NS) Dec. 2010 - April 2016

Current Studios is a digital advertising agency based in Halifax, Nova Scotia.

While at Current, I had the opportunity to work with brands such as Marvel, Disney, Coca-Cola, Volvo, and Walmart. The majority of my work was with mobile augmented reality. The tools utilized for this were Objctive-C, Java, C#, and the Unity game engine. In addition to mobile development, I was responsible for IT and Web Services. I was responsible for building out and deploying any server application that was required to support our mobile apps. These Web Services applications were usually built with Rails and deployed utilizing a variety of methods, including Heroku, VPS, and bare metal onsite. We often used tools and technologies in ways they were never intended. This fast-paced environment required projects to be shipped in as little as four weeks. As a senior developer, I was responsible for mentoring new talent. Working as a dev lead, I was responsible for delegating tasks, ensuring that deadlines were met, and communicating the status of the project to the COO.

### Education

Certificates of Completion @ Big Nerd Ranch (Atlanta, GA) 2009, 2012, 2013

Ruby on Rails, OpenGL, Javascript

Certificate of Completion @ Splice Training (Atlanta, GA) 2013

Objective-C / iOS

## Bachelor of Arts @ Mount Allison University (Sackville, NB) 2003 - 2008

Classical Studies / Software Development

## Skills

Ruby on Rails	Ruby	Objective-C	Docker	Javascript	Sass	HTML
AWS	Devops	Swift	Linux	Heroku	Git	Java
Capistrano	React	CircleCI	Solr	GraphQL	Redis	C#